人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  阿好
・ 翻译  麦结
■
・ 翻译  紫杉
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
・ 翻译  紫玉
■
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
・ 翻译  天朝直属
somehacker
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
Jessie  Sage  Kallen  吉吉  Jessie  Sage  Kallen  吉吉  Jessie  Sage  Kallen  吉吉  Jessie  Sage  Kallen  吉吉
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第一集
你明天干嘛
What are you doing tomorrow?
我认真的
I'm serious.
我们应该再来一次
We should do it again sometime.
乐队不错
Band was good.
你真美
You look fabulous.
嘴真甜
You're so sweet.
打扰你的约会了  拉斐尔
身为外交官的儿子  泡妞肯定容易吧
Must be easy to get beautiful women when you are a diplomat's son.
她能活命
She'll live.
而你  兄弟  要怪就怪你老子吧
You, amigo, you can blame your old man.
[西班牙语]是谁
Quien es?
要是你父亲之前放聪明点儿
If your father had been smart enough
乖乖跟毒帮合作
to work with the cartel...
你现在就能活着跟她吻别了
You might have lived long enough to kiss her good night.
搞啥
What?
[西班牙语]看
Mira.
你他妈是谁
Who the hell are you?
今晚么  人质谈判专家
Tonight, hostage negotiator.
拉斐尔  来吧
Raphael, come on.
天  你是疯子
Man, you're crazy.
靠
Damn!
不用谢
You're welcome.
从来没人说谢谢
They never say thank you.
是啊  真奇怪
Yeah, I wonder why.
也许你该想想法子
Maybe if you figure out a way
在闹到天下大乱之前先把人救出来
to save them before all hell breaks loose.
谢了  卡特
Thanks, Carter.
这样倒也不错
You know, for what it's worth,
你这制服穿着挺霸气
You're looking kind of badass in that uniform.
你的照样没变  面罩倒是新的
Yours is still the same, except the mask is new.
你那些朋友们呢
So where are all your friends?
我能坦白说吗
Can I be honest?
我约你出来其实就因为你太漂亮了
I only asked you out 'cause you're drop-dead gorgeous.
不过认真坐下
But after sitting down,
与你共进晚餐之后
really getting to know you over dinner,
我发现你简直是
I realized I think you might be
我遇见过的最迷人的女人
the most fascinating woman I've ever met.
是啊  我猜你对所有女孩子都是这么说的
Yeah, I bet you say that to all the girls.
其实吧  我挺确定
In fact...I know you do.
你扒掉她们的裤子
And after you get into their pants,
再扒空她们的账户
you get into their bank accounts,
比如波拉・斯卡拉蒂
Just like you did with Paula Scarlatti.
可怜的波拉心都碎了  告诉了她混黑帮的老子
Poor Paula was so heartbroken, she told her mobbed-up old man.
他和黑帮朋友们
He and his gangster pals just put
对你的脑袋悬赏重金
a big fat bounty on your head.
我能坦白说吗
And can I be honest?
我愿意跟你出来全是因为他们
I only went out with you because of them.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
你要害死我了  你干什么呢
You're gonna get me killed. What are you doing?
给我听好了  唐
Here's the deal, Don.
你马上出城  改名换姓
You need to leave town, change your name,
另谋出路
And get some game.
马上
Start now.
感谢你解决了这一问题  肖女士
I appreciate you resolving this situation, Ms. Shaw.
不过  以后
However, perhaps in the future,
执行任务时
you might try to complete your assignments
请勿如此暴力
without quite so much violence.
你看到她干啥了么  我可不是人肉盾牌
You see what she did? I'm not a human shield.
的确不是  就是挡那儿了
No, he just got in the way.
得了  我可不跟神经病合作
That's it--I'm not working with a lunatic.
我走人
I'm out.
你知道怎么找到我
You know how to find me.
我们心里早就有数了  芬奇
Can't say we didn't already know, Finch.
第一次见面  肖就开枪打我
First time we met, Shaw shot me.
我知道肖女士是得力的执行人
I realize that Ms. Shaw is an effective asset,
但我不太乐意跟这种
But I'm not sure I can work with somebody
非工作时间连手机都不带的人合作
who refuses to carry a cell phone off the job.
外面有人想杀她  你知道的
People out there are trying to kill her, you know.
这批人也同样想杀我们
Some of the same people that are trying to kill us.
是啊  看来机器还在给他们号码
Yes, machine still seems to be giving them numbers.
警察幸运收到线报
汽车行李箱内查获放射性元素"钸"
它到底还有何意图令人琢磨不透
Whatever else it's up to is almost too troubling to contemplate.
现在  我们的新号码
Meantime, our latest number--
海军中士杰克・萨拉查
Petty officer second class Jack Salazar,
美国海军
United states navy.
海军士官  还是海军罪犯
Petty officer, or petty criminal?
只怕是兼而有之
Bit of both, I'm afraid.
他五年前曾在酒吧袭击他人
He assaulted a man during a barroom brawl five years ago.
科罗拉多舰
把人打致昏迷
He all but put the guy in a coma.
法官让他选择  入狱还是从军
The judge gave him a choice: jail or the military.
杰克选择了海军
And Jack chose the navy.
他来这儿干嘛
So what's he doing here?
纽约海军周
Fleet week.
一年一度的满大街烂醉水手
The annual deluge of drunken sailors
居然还不算武装袭击
that somehow does not qualify as a military attack.
得了  芬奇  不过是一群小伙子
Come on, Finch, it's just a bunch of cracker jacks
出来放松一下
blowing off steam.
午夜就要回舰了
Then it's back to the boat by midnight.
恐怕这无数的制服水手
I'm afraid countless sailors in uniform
会让我们很难定位萨拉查先生
are going to complicate our efforts to locate Mr. Salazar.
如果杰克就像大部分水手  酒精  女人
If Jack's like most sailors, it's booze, broads,
加纹身  顺序都不会差
and a tattoo-- in that order.
看来你熟门熟路啊
I suppose you know the usual haunts.
当然  曼哈顿西部的威士忌加啤酒买一送一
Sure, it's two-for-one boilermakers in Hell's Kitchen.
听着都可怕
That sounds horrible.
走
Heel.
威士忌
Whiskey.
第六家酒吧了  芬奇
That's six bars down, Finch.
太好了  只剩下1274家了
Excellent. Only 1,274 to go.
再来一轮
Another round?
你请客就行  杰克
Only if you're buying, Jack.
等等  看到那水手了  芬奇
Wait a second. Got eyes on our sailor, Finch.
于是我就这样  跟部队失散了
So there I am, separated from my team,
深入朝鲜敌后  身上只带了巴克刀和M9
deep in North Korea with nothing but my buck knife and my M9.
我有没有漏了啥  杰克
Am I leaving anything out, Jack?
漏了鳄鱼  毒镖  还有你的脸皮么
Crocodiles, poisonous darts, your sense of shame?
我就要说到了
I'm getting to that.
上帝啊  你做了什么
Oh, my God. What did you do?
宝贝  这说来话长了  我只能待到午夜
Baby, that's a long story, and I'm only here till midnight,
所以我们何不去个安静点儿的地方
so why don't we go someplace quiet,
我详细跟你说说
and I can tell you all about it?
艾希莉  走吧
Ashley, let's go.
我想这位女士想留下来
I think the lady wants to stay.
去你的  锅盖头[陆战队员]
Screw you, Jarhead.
我不是锅盖头[陆战队员]  是水兵
I'm not a Jarhead, I'm a squid,
不过也轮不到你这种货色骂我
but a tube steak like you doesn't get to call me either.
算了  RJ  我们是来找乐子的
Leave it, RJ. We're here to have a good time.
谁都不想惹麻烦
Nobody wants trouble.
有人骂锅盖头[陆战队员]吗
Somebody call somebody "Jarhead"?
哥们儿  别这样  我请你们喝一杯
Look, man, don't do this. Let me buy you guys a round.
是啊  我正想呢
Yeah, I could use another.
你给我捡起来
You're gonna need to pick that up.
否则呢  水兵
Or what, squid?
你们这些臭鱼烂虾能怎么样呢
One of you splittails gonna do something about it?
他会冲你来上一拳
He's gonna have to take a swing at you.
然后你的兄弟就会冲我来
Then your knuckle-dragger buddy over here is gonna jump me.
等他被打得屁股向下平沙落雁了
After I introduce his face to the bar,
我会把脚踩到你的锅盖头上
I'm gonna put this foot upside of your jarhead...
最终闹个天下大乱
Upon which all hell breaks loose.
谁也不想那样
And nobody wants that.
我喜欢这家伙  芬奇
I like this guy, Finch.
里瑟先生  那边没事吧
Mr. Reese? Everything all right?
没事  登岸假罢了  芬奇
Yeah, just shore leave, Finch.
警察
Cops!
快跑
Let's get outta here!
看来我跟丢杰克了
Looks like I lost Jack.
芬奇  城里现在有多少水兵
Finch, how many squids are there in the city right now?
估计六千  问这干嘛
Approximately 6,000. Why do you ask?
我看咱们得要支援帮忙找了
I think we're gonna need backup just to find them.
全体动员
All hands on deck.
多重化名
格罗夫斯  萨姆莎
我小的时候  感觉电脑比人更亲切
When I was a kid, computers made more sense to me than people.
又名
戴森  凯利
威胁评估
图灵  卡洛琳
又名
你说过想放机器自由
You said you wanted to set the machine free.
我已经放了
I already did.
威胁消除
我叫根
My name is root.
运行诊断
求你说话啊
Please talk to me.
你  能  听见  我吗
Can... you... hear... me?
重置任务
新任务指派：模拟互动界面
当然
Absolutely.
罗宾  我刚说的话你听到了吗
Robin, did you hear anything I just said?
监控关键执行人
好吧
Okay.
有病人向我抱怨
Look, some of the patients have complained
你说话说到半夜
about you talking late into the night,
这里严禁手机
And since cell phones are strictly forbidden
你又没有室友  我只能认为
and you have no roommate, I can only conclude
你是在自言自语
that you're talking to yourself.
是这样吗
Is that correct?
你不会理解的
You wouldn't understand.
说来试试
Try me.
我可以直接与更高的力量交流
I have a direct line to a higher power.
它对我说话
It speaks to me.
明白了
I see.
这么说  你有听到声音
So you're hearing voices.
那些声音跟你说什么了
What are those voices telling you to do?
其实只有一个声音
It's just the one voice really.
它要我留在这里  解决我的问题
It wants me to stay here, to work through some issues.
那是什么问题呢
And what issues would those be?
方法论
Methodology.
我们在讨论我如何行事
We're discussing how I go about things.
不只你一个人
You're not alone.
到处报道说
All these news reports
政府在监控我们的网络生活
about government monitoring our digital lives,
记录短信  邮件  电话
recording texts, emails, phone calls,
确实令人不安
It's unsettling.
很容易让人感觉受侵犯  甚至偏执
You know, it's easy to feel violated, even paranoid.
我问你
Let me ask you this:
你感觉  自己在被监视吗
do you have feelings that you're being watched?
偶尔
Every now and then.
知道那水手是受害人还是行凶者吗
Any idea whether our sailor's a victim or a perpetrator yet?
不清楚  不过他倒是挺能打
No, but he sure knows how to handle himself in a fight.
还有其它信息吗
What else we got on this guy?
去年他绩评全优  最高分
He scored all fives on his evals last year, highest marks.
体能测试也很优秀
Same on his physical readiness test.
海军方面可能对他另有计划
The navy may have bigger plans for him.
他的合同还有六个月到期了  就可以走了
His contract's up in six months. He'll be free to go.
能找到他的其它测试吗
Can you find out if he's taken any other tests?
学术或应变测试
Academic or pst exams?
我查下  不过
I will, although it seems like
一个登岸假就能卷入酒吧斗殴
getting into a bar room brawl on shore leave
可不像前途无量的军人应为之事
is not very prudent for someone with further military aspirations.
不是杰克挑起的  他还想解决纷争
Jack didn't start that fight, but he was willing to finish it.
换我也会如此
I would've done the same thing.
他的登岸搭档有麻烦
His shore leave buddy was in trouble.
罗伯特・约翰森・菲利普斯
Robert Johnson Phillips,
海军下士  军舰仓管
Petty officer third class and ship storekeeper.
惹麻烦的能力可不"下"  他们是舰友
And first class troublemaker. They're shipmates.
也就是说他们
Which means that they'll have to
午夜后得一起回舰报到
sign back into the ship together after midnight.
找个有入伍经历的帮手
It might help us to enlist another asset
应该能帮我们追踪
with military experience to help track them down.
放过我吧  下次不敢了
Just let me go, huh? I won't do it again.
抓到这家伙又在公园露鸟了
Caught this one flashing his junk in the park again.
全是水手们进城给刺激的
All excited about the randy sailors in town.
卡特  你来干嘛呢
Carter, what are you doing here?
我第三次在哈德逊河公园里抓到他了
Third time I caught this guy in Hudsonriver Park,
这倒提醒了我
which makes me think
他很可能知道点儿
he might know something about
昨天你那起凶杀案的事儿
that homicide you caught there yesterday.
谢谢你费心
I appreciate you looking out.
我还是警察  弗斯科
Look, I'm still a cop, Fusco.
你的新搭档如何
How's your new partner?
就块木头
Guy's a box of rocks.
这事儿挺扯蛋  大家都知道
This whole thing's a crock, everybody knows
你为开那枪背了黑锅
you got hosed on that shooting.
怎么  难道还要你街上巡逻
What, do they expect you to push around a squad car
十年不成
the next ten years?
走着瞧吧
Till I get my 20.
你现在就打卡下班啊
You just now clocking out?
我们那朋友
Our mutual friend.
看来是刚刚开始上班
Looks like your day job just began.
我是卡特
Carter.
查了曼哈顿西区的每间酒吧
Checked every bar in hell's kitchen,
西区每间纹身店
Every tattoo parlor on the west side.
一个水兵到底还能去哪儿
Where the hell else would a swabbie go?
找乐子  他可是水手
To get some. He's a sailor.
进来
Come here.
女士
Ma'am.
为什么来这儿
Why are we stopping here?
我告诉过你  这里是限制区域
I told you, this area is restricted.
水手不应该出现在这儿
Sailors aren't supposed to be here.
海军几时禁了熏牛肉
When did the navy outlaw pastrami?
看到那电话了吗  看着
See that phone booth? Just watch.
市长知道有这地方吗
The mayor know about this place?
他要知道  风化组就得关停这里
If he did, vice would have to shut it down.
然后  有一半纽约警察就得
But then, half the NYPD would have to find
找新地方开单身派对了
a new place for bachelor parties.
你还撑得住吗  卡特
How are you holding up, Carter?
要不要找份新工作
You looking for a new job?
我是警察  永远都是  约翰
I'm a cop. Always will be, John.
找到那水手了
Just found our swabbie.
这次他可逃不掉了  失陪了
He's not getting away this time. Excuse me.
能请你喝一杯吗  女士
Get you a drink, Ma'am?
别叫我女士就成
Only if you stop calling me Ma'am.
? She was made to blow you away ? ?
来杯波旁
Shot of bourbon.
要人陪吗  水手
Looking for company, sailor?
只要你有钱  我随时奉陪
You got the cash, I got the open window.
承情了
Appreciate the opportunity,
不过我想找认真的
But I was kinda looking for the real thing.
复制手机
我有钱  宝贝
I got the cash, darling,
可不是随时奉陪哟
And a rapidly closing window, huh?
悠着点  哥们
Easy there, killer.
足够要她  再开个房了
That oughta cover her and the room.
别玩太疯了
Try not to get rolled.
谢了  杰克
Thanks, Jack.
这个也给你
You should take these too.
雪茄
Cigars?
不只是雪茄  古巴产的
Not just cigars, Cubans.
舰队司令用军舰运了点儿
The admiral needed a few cases shipped off the boat,
我顺了几支  小事一桩
So I taxed him a few. No big deal.
我们明天好好庆祝
We'll celebrate tomorrow.
成天顺  RJ
Always skimming something, RJ.
别阴沟里翻船
Don't get your hand caught in the cookie jar.
一小时后回来  行吗
Meet back in an hour. Can you do that?
瞧瞧她
Look at her.
我30分钟就回来
I'll be back in 30.
我是RJ  你懂的
It's RJ. You know the drill.
RJ  你到底跑哪去了
RJ, where the hell are you?
还有不到一小时我们就得滚回舰上
We got less than an hour to get our ass back on the ship.
回电话
Call me.
杰克找不到他的登岸搭档了
Jack lost his shore leave buddy.
一个人不能回去报到
Can't check back in without him.
水兵
Squid.
还记得我吗
Remember me?
记得  舰上见过  有事吗
Yeah, from the ship. Is there a problem?
是的  你知道是什么事
Yeah, you know what the problem is.
你拿了  我们想要回来
You have it, we want it back.
说实话  我不知道你在说什么
Honestly, I don't know what you're talking about, man.
麻烦大了  芬奇
Much bigger problem, Finch.
几位陆战魔在找杰克麻烦
Some devil dog's got a bone to pick with Jack.
陆战魔
Devil dogs?
是啊  特种部队  陆战侦察兵
Yeah, spec ops, force recon marines.
一共四个人  也许五个
Team of four, maybe five.
把出路都封死了
Just sealed off the block.
如果我直接冲过去
If I go straight in,
能近身之前杰克就没命了
Jack'll be dead before I even get to him.
别搞我们  否则搞死你
You don't screw with us. We screw you.
口袋里的东西掏出来
Empty your pockets.
哥们儿  我没时间搞这个
Look, man, I don't really have time for this.
我得找到舰友  我得
I gotta get my shipmate, and I gotta get--
他们在偷车  准备走人
They're stealing a car. It's an extraction.
我得救他
I gotta get him out.
千万小心  里瑟先生
Please be careful, Mr. Reese.
感觉到了吗
Feel that?
是你的肋骨在叫
That's your rib cracking.
再深五厘米  就会刺进你的肺里
I jam it 2 inches further, I'm gonna puncture your lung.
东西在哪
Where is it?
我不知道你在说什么
Don't know what you're talking about, man.
把他跟他搭档关一起  解决他们
Get him and his buddy to a room. We'll sort 'em out.
搞什么
What the hell?
那是谁
Who is that?
芬奇  水手中枪了  需要帮助
Finch, our sailor took fire. Gonna need some help.
水兵醒之前得先把子弹取出来
Let's get this bullet out before the squid wakes up.
能崩你也能救你  说实话  我无所谓
Could shoot you or save you. Frankly, I could go either way.
放松  萨拉查  我们是好人
Easy, Salazar. We're the good guys.
我就知道这是个坏主意
I knew this was a bad idea.
你们是谁  我在哪
Who are you people? Where am I?
有颗子弹在你肩膀里  萨拉查先生
You have a bullet lodged in your shoulder, Mr. Salazar,
愤怒的陆战侦察魔留下的礼物
a gift from a very angry group of force recon devil dogs,
我只能说他们真是名副其实
whom I can only assume live up to their name.
这位肖女士有医疗救护经验
Now, Ms. Shaw has medical experience,
因此要么你让她帮你取出子弹
so either you can either let her retrieve the bullet,
或者我们继续讨论此事
or we can continue to discuss the matter
直到你患上败血症
until you contract sepsis.
你确定会处理吗
Sure you know what you're doing?
我中过枪  很多
I've been shot... a lot.
要告诉我们为什么一队精英杀手要追杀你么
You wanna tell us why a squad of elite killers is after you?
不知道
Don't know.
他们在索马里打击什么
Guys were in Somalia doing god knows what--
反叛组织
fighting rebels.
指挥官有个战利品想带回来  AK47
Leader had a war trophy he wanted to bring back, AK-47.
我把它藏在一箱旧铜器里
I stashed it in a crate of spent brass.
你帮他们走私非法武器
So you helped them smuggle an illegal weapon
通过美国海关
through U.S. Customs?
这种事很平常
It happens all the time.
我兄弟RJ卸的箱子
My buddy RJ unloaded the crate,
说已经把枪还了
said he gave back the rifle.
这没道理啊
It doesn't add up.
他们为什么要为了把武器杀他
Why would they try to kill him over a weapon?
不是为了武器  肖女士
It's not the weapon, Ms. Shaw.
是为了藏在里面的东西
It's what was hidden inside it.
美国海军夺回被劫矿船
索马里海盗在非洲沿海抢了一艘
Somali pirates attacked a deep-sea mining vessel
深海采矿船
off the coast of Africa.
那几位海军朋友介入了此事
Your marine friends intervened.
什么矿
What kind of mining?
开免提
Speaker.
装货小子  你忘了登岸搭档制度
Bagger, you forgot it's the buddy system.
指登岸搭档必须一起回舰报道
我们抓了你的搭档
We got your buddy.
抱歉  杰克  我搞砸了
Sorry Jack, I screwed up.
我顺了点儿  就一点
Look, I taxed 'em. It was just a few.
我以为他们不会在意
I didn't think they'd miss 'em!
在意什么  你在说什么
Miss what? What're you talking about?
看那些古巴雪茄
Check the Cubans.
未切割原石
Uncut stones.
那是钻石采矿船
The ship was mining diamonds.
想让你兄弟活着回来  杰克
You want to see your buddy alive, Jack,
就把石子儿带到巴高克酒店212房间
bring the rocks to the Babcock, room 212.
一个人来
Come alone.
我们还没聊过你的家人
We really haven't talked about your family
还有朋友  罗宾
or friends, Robin.
你叔叔哈罗德  是他安排你住院的
Your uncle--Harold, is it-- who arranged your admission.
你跟他亲近吗
Are you close with him?
这个
That's...
很复杂  医生
a complicated question, Doctor.
我希望能全力配合你的工作
I wouldn't want to be anything less than totally forthcoming,
不如换个话题吧
So maybe we should try another subject.
好吧
Okay.
你说希望
You say that you don't want to be
全力配合我
anything less than forthcoming...
但却跟我撒谎
And yet, you're lying to me.
正相反  我绝对坦诚
On the contrary, I've been completely honest.
抱歉
Please, excuse me.
也许不太"绝对"
Maybe not completely.
我以为自己弄丢了  原来是你偷了
I thought I lost this, and it turns out it was stolen.
抱歉  医生
I'm sorry, Doctor,
但是我们一定要保持联系
But it's important we be in contact.
我们有点
We're in the middle of a...
争执
disagreement.
你和那个声音有争执
A disagreement with the voice?
我希望你知道  我无条件支持你
I want you to know that I support you unconditionally.
我理解你认为自己需要电话
Now, I know you believe you need a phone,
但我还是要说  你不需要
And I'm here to tell you that you don't.
我相信禁止你碰它
I believe that by separating you from it--
以及其他所有科技产品
and from all other forms of technology--
是目前的最佳方法
It's really the best course of action.
拒绝科技吧
So it's time to unplug.
请几位助手进来
Some assistance, please.
拜托  别这样
Please... don't do this.
不能把我们分开
It's not good for us to be separated.
希望你明白  我是在帮你
I hope you realize I'm trying to help you.
把这位病人送到隔离病房
Escort our patient to solitary confinement.
不得接触任何电子设备
No contact with anything electronic.
有朝一日你会感谢我
You'll thank me someday.
身为心理医生
For a psychiatrist,
你真是太不会看人了
you're really a terrible judge of character.
我们来这干什么
What are we doing here?
侦察
Recon.
十点在那儿交易
The exchange goes down there in ten.
那里  特种部队肯定安排有狙击手
That's it. Spec ops will have a sniper.
要我就会在那里
That's where I'd be.
有零钱吗
You got any cash?
你好啊
Hola, mija.
真不知道我怎么会落到这步田地
Don't know how I wound up here.
我知道
I do.
和你跟锅盖头打架是一个原因
Same reason you got into a fight with those jarheads.
你为自己在乎的人挺身而出
You stand up for people you care about.
我是大受其益啊
Lotta good it's done me, huh?
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
本性难移
You can't be something you're not.
是吗  那我的本性是什么
Yeah? And who am I?
你是好人  杰克
You're a good guy, Jack.
只是你自己还没明白
You just haven't figured it out yet.
谢谢
Gracias.
干嘛  要帮忙找垃圾桶吗
What, you need help finding a trash can?
你聪明啊  自己想该怎么用
You're a smart guy, you'll figure out what to do with it.
给我三分钟
Give me three minutes.
陆战队的武器妙啊
Our leatherneck has a nice weapon.
这下就好玩了
This is gonna be fun.
记住
Just remember...
不许射要害
no shots to center mass.
这么好的枪拿来打膝盖可惜了
But it's a shame to waste a rifle like this on kneecaps.
没岗哨  不对劲
No sentry. Something's up.
能看到房间里吗  有谁
You got eyes on the room? Who's there?
空荡荡
Looks vacated.
情有可原  那可怜人被装上炸弹了
For good reason, poor guy's rigged up to go boom.
别
Don't.
别引爆了
Can't risk setting him off.
你朋友坐在简易炸弹上
Your friend's sitting on an IED.
抱歉把你卷进来  杰克
Look, I'm sorry I got you into this, Jack,
但你要是能把我弄出去
But if you can get me outta here,
我发誓会承担一切责任
I swear I'll rap to everything.
放松  你没事的
Take it easy. You're gonna be okay.
那可不一定
I wouldn't say that.
我们说过要一个人来  你却带上了这西装男
We told you to come alone. You brought the suit,
那他也要跟着倒霉了
So now he's a guest at our party.
他要走  我们就按按钮  RJ爆炸
He tries to leave, we hit a button, RJ explodes.
你敢动RJ  他爆炸
You try to move RJ, he explodes.
明白了吗  水兵
You understand me, squid?
知道了
I get the gist.
毁掉手机
Destroy your phone.
路边有辆出租车  载你去下一站
There's a cab on the curb that'll take you to the next location,
一个人
alone.
你出了那门  杰克
You walk out that door, Jack,
可能就回不来了
you won't come back.
RJ是我的朋友
RJ's my friend.
你也说过
You said it yourself.
本性难移
I can't be something I'm not.
哈罗德  交易有变
Harold, the exchange went pear-shaped.
我听到了  你能跟踪萨拉查先生吗
Yes, I heard. Can you follow Mr. Salazar?
不行  他已经走远了
Not an option. He's long gone.
还没试试这小可爱呢
Never even got to take this baby out for a test drive.
那些未切割钻石  陆战队员肯定得销赃
The marines will have to fence the uncut diamonds.
找到销赃的  我们应该就能找到杰克
Locate the fence, odds are we can locate Jack.
现在去哪儿
Where to now?
我另有人手在追查此事
I have another resource working on that.
你自便
Suit yourself.
抢劫组那边有消息吗
Any luck with your contacts in robbery?
还没有  别担心  我有路子
Not yet. Don't worry, I got a source.
关机
不是说表现良好可以放假么
What happened to time off for good behavior?
前提是你表现良好
That assumes you've been good.
我们有约定  你要保持低调
We had a deal, you keep a low profile.
否则我何必在地下室享受巴罗洛呢
Why else would I be enjoying my Barolo in a basement?
你的人在皇冠高地出现了
Your man's been seen in Crown Heights,
那是俄罗斯人的地盘
Russian territory.
现在全城都是俄罗斯人的地盘了
It's all Russian territory now.
让我们单独聊下
Give us a moment, alone.
谢谢你  救了我老大
Thank you... for helping my boss.
看看你  都交上朋友了
What do you know, you've made a friend.
说到朋友  我不禁注意到
Speaking of, I can't help but notice
哈罗德和约翰都没来看望过我
that I haven't received a visit from Harold or John.
你还没有告诉他们  是吧
Haven't told them yet, have you?
怕他们反对我们的小约定吗
Afraid they'd object to our little deal?
没有约定  我是别无选择
There's no deal, okay, I had no choice.
如果我把你重新关进监狱
If I'd put you back in prison,
就会有人  警察或是俄罗斯人
someone--cops or the Russians--
迟早都会杀了你
would've killed you sooner or later.
我要一个名字
I need a name,
有办法销赃大批未切割钻石的人
someone with the means to fence large quantities of uncut diamonds.
如果有人想要做这样的交易
If someone is interested in such a transaction,
他们必须要联系个快速销赃人
They'd have to connect with a mobile fence,
有个不择手段的俄罗斯人
and I can think of an unscrupulous Russian
名字叫马克西姆
by the name of Maksim,
他在熨斗区经营一间当铺
presently operating out of a pawn shop in the Flatiron District.
小心  这很危险  警探
Careful, this is dangerous business, Detective.
现在是警员了
It's officer now.
多可惜啊  我最恨暴殄天物
Such a shame, I hate seeing talent go to waste.
我可以搞垮HR和俄罗斯人
I could take care of HR and the Russians...
永远地
permanently.
享受你的巴罗洛吧
Enjoy the rest of your Barolo.
情况如何  芬奇
How's it going, Finch?
我拦截了手机信号塔的信号
I've intercepted the signal at the cell tower.
制作了一个循环影像
I'm creating a loop to send
发送给他们的头目
back down the line to the team leader.
他看不到你离开房间
It'll appear to him as if you never left the room.
完成  你可以离开了  里瑟先生
All done. You can leave, Mr. Reese.
我建议你快点走  我派了增援
I suggest you do so in a hurry. I've sent reinforcements.
谁
Who?
你们真是一刻不消停
Never a dull moment with you guys.
给  卡特给的
Here, Carter came through.
是熨斗区的一处销赃地址
Address for the fence in the Flatiron District.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
那些老毛子凶狠残忍  火力强大
These ruskies are ruthless and packin' serious heat.
这活儿适合肖
Sounds like a job for Shaw.
还有  这位身上的炸弹得拆
Besides, someone needs to defuse that bomb.
加油  莱奈尔
Hup to, Lionel.
什么  没人跟我说要拆炸弹
What? Nobody said anything about defusing a bomb.
小心点  有断电保护
Be careful, it's got a fail safe.
如果切断电源  就会爆炸
If you try to cut the power source, it'll blow,
所以要拆掉点火装置
So dig out the igniter.
啥装置
The what?
你的石子儿我带来了  你不敢出来玩了吗
I got your rocks. You afraid to come out and play?
你还以为是你说了算吗  水手小子
You still think you're in charge of this little operation, swab-jockey?
不好说  反正我捏着你的货
Don't know. I got your whole stash.
好啊  我捏着小小的保险  你的兄弟RJ
Yeah, well, I got a little insurance policy, your buddy RJ.
23大街和莱辛顿大道的十字路口有家当铺
There's a pawn shop at 23rd and Lex.
那又怎么了
What about it?
你跟销赃人玩个"谈交易"的游戏
You're gonna play "Let's make a deal" with our fence.
你把钻石给他  然后换来现金带给我们
You bring him the diamonds and you bring us the cash.
你要是耍什么花招  就等着被收尸吧
You tries to pull a fast one, you end up in a body bag.
时间不等人  海军士官
Time's ticking, petty officer.
陆战魔要过多久会发现
How long before the devil dog realizes
你朋友篡改了影像
your friend switched the video?
很久  但愿吧
Long enough... let's hope.
你是海军  知道点火装置在哪儿吗
You're in the navy. Know anything about igniters?
伙计  我是个"光荣"的仓管员
Man, I'm a glorified shopkeeper.
只管补给品
I inventory supplies.
别担心  我是警察
Don't worry, I'm a cop.
拆弹组的
Bomb squad?
凶案组的
Homicide.
当铺
有东西要给我吗
You have something for me?
你不是跟我通电话的人
You're not the one who I talked to on the phone.
是游客吗
You're a tourist?
可以这么说
Guess you could say that.
那你只能拿到游客价  面值的30%
Then you get the tourist rate. 30 cents on the dollar.
等等  你不明白你搞的是什么人
Wait, you don't understand who you're screwing with.
什么人  没枪没支援的人
Who? A man with no gun and no backup?
也许我们会留下钱和钻石
Maybe we keep our money and your diamonds.
我们不二价
We don't renegotiate.
天天刀口舔血
Another fine navy day.
你一定是马克西姆吧
You must be Maksim.
你说过是面值的50%
You said 50 cents on the dollar.
那是在我看到货之前
That was before I saw the merchandise.
你之前没说是非洲货
You failed to mention it's from Africa.
你不走运  我读了报道
Unfortunately for you, I have read all about
知道海盗被陆战队拿下的事
the pirates and the marine heroes who took them down.
来见你  风险很大
Took big risk, coming, meeting you.
风险越大  价格越低
Risk goes up, price goes down.
我给一百二
I give you 1.2.
你觉得要给我多少我才不会干掉你
How much for me to not put a bullet in your brain?
把枪放下
Put your weapon down!
不好意思  你们打烊了吗
I'm sorry, are you guys closed?
当铺
气氛有点紧张
It's a bit tense in here.
我提个建议如何
Can I make a suggestion?
你在这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
这是什么人  警察吗
Who is this, cop?
相关第三方  我跟这事儿无关
Concerned third party. I've got no stake in this
只是想帮我朋友杰克
except for helping my friend Jack out of here
四肢健全  一洞不多地离开
with the same number of holes he had in him when he came in.
什么意思
What's your point?
面值的40%如何
40 cents on the dollar?
里瑟  无意冒犯
Reese, no offense,
哪天要是义警做不下去了
if the vigilante thing doesn't work out,
我看你在调停方面也是前途无亮
I'm not really seeing a future for you in conflict resolution.
这位西装男
The suit here,
刚刚害死了你的兄弟
he just got your buddy killed.
警探  出去  快
Detective, get out, now!
没时间了
There's no time.
拜了
Goodbye.
就说了我能搞定
I told you I got it covered.
建议你免开尊口
I suggest you keep your mouth shut.
按之前谈好的办  不然就得死
And you give us what you agreed to or we kill you.
你觉得你们牛逼是吗
You think you're pretty tough, no?
美国陆战魔
U.S. Devil dogs.
满世界转悠  杀几个伊拉克人
Run around, kill Iraqis,
杀几个阿富汗人  索马里人
kill Afghans, Somalis.
知道什么人你们不敢杀吗
You know who you don't kill?
俄罗斯人
Russians.
里瑟  俄罗斯人为什么在后退
Reese, why are the Russians backing up?
知道吗  我加入海军陆战队就是为了杀俄罗斯人
You know what, I enlisted in the marines to kill Russians.
看来我终于有机会了
Looks like I'm gonna get my chance.
等等
Wait a minute...
看起来俄罗斯人还带了朋友过来
Looks like the Russians brought some friends to the party.
你上面有好几个枪手  里瑟
Multiple shooters above you, Reese.
现在闪开
Get clear, now.
要打埋伏  记得用消音器
You gonna ambush somebody, use a muzzle suppressor.
废物
Losers.
肖  帮把手行不
Shaw, a little help here?
我可以爆头的
I would have taken the head shot,
可我一杀人芬奇就唧唧歪歪
but Finch gets annoyed when I kill people.
正中胳膊  穿过砖墙  越过黑暗
In the arm, through a brick wall, in the dark?
不用谢
You're welcome.
想离开这儿吗
You want to get out of here?
当然
Yeah, I think so.
? Birds flying high you know how I feel ?
? Sun in the sky you know how I feel ?
该把你朋友送回舰上去了
Time to get your friend back to the ship
午夜的钟声要响了
before he turns into a pumpkin.
你倒挺得心应手
You're pretty handy with that thing.
? Breeze driftin' on by you know how I feel ?
我饿了  给我买牛排
I'm hungry. You're buying me a steak.
? It's a new dawn it's a new day ?
? It's a new life for me yeah ?
? It's a new life for me ?
? And I'm feeling good ?
? Fish in the sea ?
? You know how I feel ?
? River running free, you know how I feel ?
? Blossom on the tree ?
? You know how I feel ?
? It's a new dawn it's a new day ?
? It's a new life for me ?
? And I'm feeling good ?
听说熨斗区有枪击案
Heard about the shoot-out in the Flatiron district.
大量伤亡啊  约翰  人救出来了吗
Lotta damage, John, you get your man out alive?
有人相助  没问题
With a little help.
卡特  你还好吗
Listen, Carter, you doing okay?
我们很久没坐下来聊聊了
It's been a while since we sat down and talked.
我还好  约翰  工作罢了
I'm fine, John, you know, just getting on with my job.
如果你需要帮助的话
You know if you ever needed help...
一个电话就好  知道吗
you just need to call me, right?
我知道  谢谢
I know. Thanks.
? For me yeah, yeah ?
? Stars, when you shine you know how I feel ?
? Scent of the pine, you know how I feel ?
? Oh, freedom is mine ?
? And I know how I feel ?
纽约文汇
警探与毒贩枪战殉职
? It's a new dawn, it's a new day ?
? It's a new life for me ?
庆祝还是消愁
Celebrating or commiserating?
都是
Both.
RJ承担了所有的责任
RJ took the rap for everything.
舰长训了我半天
Captain gave me a desk-drawer reprimand
罚我擦两天的甲板
and two days swabbing the deck.
我还剩一小时自由时间
I got an hour left of liberty
之后就得回到舰上
before I gotta get back on the ship.
那你现在有何计划
So what's the plan now?
舰长看好我  加入海豹突击队
Captain thinks I could make it through buds, become a seal,
不过在经历了这些之后
but after what happened,
我不怎么信任军队了
I'm not so sure about the military anymore.
也许这趟下来  我能回归正常生活
Thought maybe there was a chance for a normal life after my tour's up,
就像那一对儿
like those two.
军队里有善有恶
The military's full of good and bad,
就像其他地方一样
just like the rest of the world.
像你这样的人足以行善
A guy like you could do a lot of good.
本来我就是被迫入伍的
I was forced to join in the first place.
怎么  你以为只有你年少时被迫
What, you think you're the first kid to have to
站在法官面前  选择另一种人生吗
stand in front of a judge and pick door number two?
结果  我挺擅长
Turns out, I was good at it.
如天生一样
Maybe even made for it.
你也一样  你很有天赋
So are you. With your talent,
也许不用多久  中情局就会来找你了
it probably won't be long before the CIA comes knocking.
那我该怎么做
So what should I do?
那取决于你自己
That's up to you.
不过当几年之后  兰利总部的人出现时
But in a few years, when the guys from Langley show up...
拒绝
say no.
给那幸福的一对儿上两杯香槟
I'd like to buy the happy couple two glasses of champagne.
谢谢
Thanks.
你所做的一切
For everything.
做得好  里瑟先生
Nicely done, Mr. Reese.
我似乎从未亲耳听过
I realize now I never did hear
你是如何参军的
how you came to enlist in the army.
因为我从未对你说过  芬奇
'Cause I never told you, Finch.
我很注重隐私
I'm a very private person.
再一次小小的拯救了世界
One more thing set right in the universe.
你应该高兴点  哈罗德
You should look happier, Harold.
我高兴  只是
I am. It's just...
我感觉  事情会越发复杂
I have a feeling things are about to get more complicated.
那不妨享受下你的第一杯威士忌加啤酒
Then you might as well enjoy your first boilermaker.
我认为我们应该重新开始对话
I thought it would be good for us to resume our dialogue.
我理解你更想跟那个声音交谈
I know that you'd rather be talking to the voice,
不过你得将就一下了
but you're gonna have to settle for talking to me.
你想谈些什么
What do you want to talk about?
我想谈论些真实的东西  罗宾
I'd like to talk about something real, Robin.
我知道你非常聪明
I know you're very smart.
我很想知道你真正的想法
I'd love to know what you're really thinking,
所以不如谈谈真相吧
so why don't we start with the truth?
真相
The truth?
真相繁芜丛杂  我现在看清了
The truth is a vast thing. I see that now...
太多的真相  我们从何谈起
Just how much truth there is. Where would we even begin?
真相就是  你并不聪明
The truth is you are not very smart.
事实上  你只是这栋大楼里第43聪明的人
In fact, you're only the 43rd smartest person in this building.
第43
43rd?
好吧  那声音告诉你的吗
Okay, did your voice tell you that?
有何依据
That's based on what?
依据你标准化考试的平均数据
Every standardized test you ever took averaged together,
不包括你的医生资格考试
not including your medical boards,
那个你作弊了
which you cheated on.
真相就是  你平均每周抽九支烟
The truth is you smoke an average of nine cigarettes a week
都是躲在自以为没人看到的停车场
in the parking lot when you think no one's looking.
真相就是  你每一两个月就会去一次按摩院
The truth is that you visit a massage parlor once or twice a month,
每次支付都用整洁的百元现钞
that you pay for it with crisp $100 bills that
是你从对面7-11便利店的自动取款机里取出的
you get out of the cash machine at the 7-Eleven across the street.
真相就是  你在网络论坛上意淫
The truth is that you fantasize on online forums
跟自己的某些病人上床
about having sex with some of your patients,
但不是我  看来我不是你的菜
though not me... yet. I guess I'm not your type.
真相就是  上帝11岁了
The truth is, God is 11 years old,
她诞生于2002年元旦的曼哈顿
that she was born on New Year's Day, 2002, in Manhattan.
真相就是  她选择了我
The truth is that she's chosen me,
我却还不知道原因
and I don't know why yet,
然而有生以来第一次
that for the first time in my life...
我有点恐惧未来
I'm a little scared about what's gonna happen.
真相就是  我现在被困在这里
The truth is, I'm stuck here for now,
你唯一需要担心的
and the only dialogue you need to be worried about
是我与她的对话
is between me and her,
所以也许你想把手机还给我
which is why you might want to give me my phone back.
因为我们正在争论
Because I'm having an argument.
你想知道真相吗  医生
Would you like to know the truth, Doctor?
想知道我们在争论什么吗
About what we're arguing over?
我是否要杀了你
Whether or not I'm gonna kill you.
监控关键执行人
重置任务进行中
成功概率：未知